<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.bhyoo.krema</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Krema</name>
  <summary>A lightweight dock for KDE Plasma 6 — spiritual successor to Latte Dock</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Krema is a lightweight dock for KDE Plasma 6, designed as a spiritual successor
      to Latte Dock. It provides quick access to your favorite applications with
      smooth parabolic zoom animations, window previews via PipeWire, and deep
      integration with KDE Plasma desktop features.
    </p>
    <p>
      Choose from six background styles — transparent, tinted, acrylic frosted glass,
      Mica (system accent color based), and adaptive opacity that responds to
      overlapping windows. Full keyboard navigation (Meta+F5) and AT-SPI screen
      reader support ensure the dock is accessible to all users.
    </p>
    <p>
      Built from scratch with C++23 and KDE Frameworks 6, Krema is Wayland-native and
      uses Kirigami for its settings UI, ensuring a fully native KDE Plasma experience.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.bhyoo.krema.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/isac322/krema</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/isac322/krema/issues</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/isac322/krema</url>
  <developer id="com.bhyoo">
    <name>Byeonghoon Yoo</name>
  </developer>
  <provides>
    <binary>krema</binary>
  </provides>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>dock</keyword>
    <keyword>launcher</keyword>
    <keyword>taskbar</keyword>
    <keyword>panel</keyword>
    <keyword>latte</keyword>
    <keyword>kde</keyword>
    <keyword>plasma</keyword>
    <keyword>wayland</keyword>
    <keyword>zoom</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <categories>
    <category>Qt</category>
    <category>KDE</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.5.1" date="2026-03-01">
      <description>
        <p>Fixed icon rendering on HiDPI displays when icon normalization or icon scale is active. Fixed dock edge trigger unreachable in AutoHide/DodgeWindows mode when KDE panel occupies the screen edge.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.0" date="2026-03-01">
      <description>
        <p>Icon size normalization with automatic padding detection, projective SDF drop shadow, smooth icon repositioning animation on dock resize, and dock recovery after screen lock and monitor hot-plug. Merged SmartHide into DodgeWindows with DodgeActiveOnly option. Full documentation overhaul with updated feature descriptions and accessibility coverage.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-02-24">
      <description>
        <p>Six background styles (transparent, tinted, acrylic frosted glass, Mica, and adaptive opacity), and comprehensive keyboard accessibility with AT-SPI screen reader support.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-02-24">
      <description>
        <p>Window previews via PipeWire, multi-window preview list, and Settings UI improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.1" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>Bug fixes and stability improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
